Rachel St. Clair

Delray Beach, FL Phone: 561.414.9374

E-Mail: rachel.aileen.st@gmail.com

Vision

How can the differences in man and machine guide development of machine perception to supplement mankind?

Objective

Innovative thinker focused on biomedical applications of deep learning and machine perception for global advancement.

Presentations, Proceedings, and Papers

Robishaw J., StClair R., et al. "Early Detection of COVID-19 Onset Symptoms with OURA Device." Current works.

StClair R., et al. "Developmental Data Augmentation." Current works.

StClair R., Teti M., et al. "Autoimmune Antibody Binding Motif Prediction Model with LSTMs." Current works.

Perez N., StClair R., et al. "Birdsong Grammar Structure Identification from Siamese Networks." Current works.

Neil Sachdeva, StClair R., et al. "Using Conditional Generative Adversarial Networks to Reduce the Effects of Latency in Robotic Telesurgery." IEEE International Conference on Omni-layer Intelligent systems. 2020 March 6; Barcelona, Spain. Conference Proceedings. Under review.

Morris P., StClair R., et al. "Predicting Binding from Screening Assays with Transformer Network Embeddings." Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. Dec. 2019. Under Review

StClair R. "Translating Images with Generative Adversarial Networks" Data Science and Analytics Conference. 2019 Nov. 2; Boca Raton, FL. Workshop.

St. Clair R., Hahn W., et al. "Artificial Intelligence – What Does the Future (and Today) Hold?" Women Corporate Directors South Florida Chapter. 2019 Oct. 30; Boca Raton, FL. Panel discussion.

St.Clair R. "General Adversarial Networks: Brief HIstory and Overview." Max Plank Academy. 2019 Oct. 15; Boca Raton, FL. Guest lecture.

StClair R. "General Adversarial Networks." Machine Perception and Cognitive Robotics Deep Learning Short Course. 2019 Aug 13-Aug 16; Boca Raton, FL. Workshop.

StClair R. "Post-Analytics: General Statistics from Your Model." Machine Perception and Cognitive Robotics Deep Learning Short Course. 2019 Aug 13- Aug 16; Boca Raton, FL. Lecture.

Morris P., StClair R., et al. "Virtual High-Throughput Screening; A Combined Deep-Learning Approach." American Chemical Society National Conference. 2019 Mar 31- Apr 4; Orlando, FL. Lecture.

StClair R., et al. "Gold Particle Labeling with GANs" Max Plank Academy. 2019 Jan- May; Jupiter, FL. Workshop lead.

StClair R., Teti M., et al. "Self-Organizing Map Methodology for Sorting Differential Expression Data of MMP-9 Inhibition." 2019. biorxiv 586628; doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/586628.

Rachel St. Clair

Delray Beach, FL
Phone: 561.414.9374

E-Mail: rachels@mpcrlab.com

StClair R., Dawson-Scully K., et al. "C.eVICHE: C.Elegan Visual Implementation of Computational Heuristic Experiments." Poster presented at: Max Plank Sunposium Conference; 2019 Mar 4-6; West Palm Beach, FL.

Teti M., StClair R., et al. "Target Binding and Sequence Prediction With LSTMs." 2018. bioRxiv 504415; doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/504415.

StClair R., Fields G., et al. *Self-Organizing Degradomics Model: SOMMMP9. Poster presented at:* University of Miami Neuroscience Day Conference; 2018 Dec 7; Miami, FL.

Teti M., StClair R., et al. *Deep learning sequence prediction for synthetic biology and genetic engineering. Poster presented at:* International Genetically Engineered Machine Competition; 2017 Nov; Boston, MA.

Gil M., StClair R., et al. *Temporal ontogeny of epileptogenesis in a model of adult-onset, spontaneous Seizures*. Poster presented at: FAU Undergraduate Research Symposium; 2017 Mar; Boca Raton, FL.

Education

Florida Atlantic University Aug. 2018 - Fall 2021 *PhD, Complex Systems and Brain Sciences*

Florida Atlantic University May 2013 - Dec. 2017 Bachelors of Science degree, majoring in Biology

Experience

Department of Homeland Security PEPI-G Internship

May 2019 - January 2020

- Utilize Amazon Web Services and Created Report
- Cultivate prototype for two seperate computer vision problems

Deep Learning Short Course Lead Organizer, Coordinator, and Instructor

March 2019 - August 2019

- Develope and carryout organization of course and logistics
- Lead instructor for generative adversarial networks lecture, training CNNs, Post-Analysis results

MPFI Mentor January 2019 - May 2019

- Computer vision project designer and execution management
- Mentor to two students in general programming and project development

Machine Perception and Cognitive Robotics Lab

May 2017 - Current

- Biomedical solutions using deep learning
- Innovative research team dedicated to machine perception and cognitive perceptions

Alkermes Pharmaceutical Technician

March 2017 - June 2017

Bulk Line 2 Manufacturing Associate

Student Athlete Tutor October 2017 - Dec. 2018

- Biology tutor at Florida Atlantic University for student athletics department
- Developing lesson plans and inspiring students to reach their full potentials

OwlGems May 2017 – November 2017

- Research team using synthetic biology to detect counterfeit antimalarial drugs
- Team centered group that relies on self-disciplined individuals' cooperation

Undergraduate Research Trainee

Aug 2016 - May. 2017

Rachel St. Clair

Delray Beach, FL Phone: 561.414.9374

E-Mail: rachels@mpcrlab.com

- Assist in data gathering, analysis, lab techniques (PCR, Gel Electrophoresis, solution make-up, etc.),
- and lab animal care
- Train other undergraduate research trainees in data analysis and animal care

Neurosurgery Shadow

May 2015 - Aug 2015

Observed clinical and office task carried out by Dr. Eric Peterson

Neurosurgery Floor Volunteer

Aug 2014 - May 2015

- Observed daily care in 7th floor neurosurgery at Boca Regional Hospital
- Took initiated to help Rn's whenever possible by organizing, cleaning, and anticipating needs

Skills

Python Ubuntu/ Widows

Data Pre-Processing Libraries Docker

Pvtorch Video and Text Processing

Tensorflow Latex/Overleaf

Computer Vision techniques Amazon Web Services SageMaker

C++

Generative Adversarial Networks Biologics Data

Arduino

Certifications

Certified Phlebotomist Technician NHA 6/14/2016

Phlebotomy Training First Response Training 4/17/2016 Blood borne Pathogens Training First Response Training 4/17/2016

Basic Clinical Skills FAU May 2015

CNA Training First Response Training February 2015 **EKG** Training First Response Training 2/22/2014 Food Handler Certificate Myfloridafoodhandler.com 1/27/2013

Organizations

Robotics Club @ FAU 2019-Current Phi Delta Epsilon 2015-2016

Medical co-ed fraternity, marketing team member Bioinformatics Club @ FAU 2017-2018

American Medical Student Association 2014 - 2015

American Medical Women's Association 2016-2018 Member of elected board: Studio AMWA Director (local branch

title)

References

Available upon request